Now, where to begin?
该怎广开始呢 ?
How ‘bout, "Once upon a time"?
用 『「很久很久以前」 如何?
How many times have you heard that to begin a story?
这未免太老套了吧
Let's do somethin’ else.
咱们换个新花招
! got it, l got it, here we go. Here's how to open a movie!
有了，这种开场一定很况
No, ! don't think so. It sounds familiar. Doesn't it, to you?
不行，这行不通 看起来很眼熟，对吧?
Oh, no, no, not the book.
不要翻童话故事书啦
How many have seen "opening the book" before?
翻童话故事书这一招 用通凡所了
Close the book. We're not doing that.
快把书问起来 我们不用这一招
Here's what we're gonna do.
不然这柑好了
Why don't I just go back to the day
咱们就直接回到
things took a turn for the worse?
…翡惨事件发生的那一天
Run for your lives! Everyone run for cover!
快逃命呀,大家快躲起来
SOS! Mayday! Mayday!
事情大人条 了 ! 救人啊!
Code red! Duck and cover!
空闽警报，快逃命呀
You're all in danger!
你们都有生命危险
Run for cover!
快生起来
Run for your lives!
快逃命啊
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急状况，紧急状况
Look out! Take cover!
小心，快找撼访
Run for cover!
快生起来
Chicken Little! What is it? What's going on?
难丁，怎订回事 ? 发生什么事 ?
The sky is falling!
天空掉下来了 !
- The sky is falling? - Are you crazy?
天空掉下来了? 你站了吗 ?
No, no, no! It's true! Come with me!
苍没有 是真的，跟我来
No. Son? What?
儿子?什么 ?
It happened under the old oak tree!
它就掉在老橡村底下
I'm not making this up. I know it's here.
我不是里儿的，它就在那儿
There's a piece of the sky somewhere...
有一才天空掉下来
.. somewhere on the ground here.
就掉在这里的地上
It was shaped like that!
形状就像那个
- Like a stop sign? - Yes!
它像一个者停标读 ? 对
Only it doesn't say "stop" and it's blue and it has a cloud on it.
不上面没有写“停” 它是蓝的，上面有一节云
And it hit me on the head!
而且它K到我的头
- It looked like a stop sign. - Wait! What's that?
看起来是很像暂停标读 等等，那是什么 ?
- Son, is this what hit you? - What?
儿子，你被这玩意K到 ? 什么 ?
No, Dad. It was definitely a piece of the sky!
不是啦，符 那缀对是一活天空
Piece of the sky. It's OK, everyone!
列胡病了 大采儿，没事儿
- Dad, no. - There's been, like, a little mistake.
和葡，不… 这只是小小的误解
It was just an acorn that hit my son. A little acorn.
我儿子被一颗橡树果K到 一晒小小的橡机果
- No! Dad, no. - Quiet, son.
不是啦，符 副说了，儿子
This is embarrassing enough already.
这已经金于脸了
Chicken Little! What were you thinkin'?
难丁，你到底在想什么 ?
Why put your town's safety in jeopardy?
你差点害死全镇居民
How could you mistake a stop sign for an acorn?
你怎订会把橡桂果 看成交通标读?
- But it... a big acorn level fluh. - What did he say?
但…那是…大橡树果花啦啦 他说什么 ?
- Abig acorn level fluh... - It was a big acorn?
大橡树果花啦啦 那是大橡树果花啦啦
- It was an ape throwing coleslaw? - Abig acorn level fluh...
那是大猩猩在溜渭梯 ? 大橡树果花啦啦
Gesundheit!
笑死人了
Ladies and gentlemen, it's just gibberish,
各位，他在胡言秽语
- gibberish of an insane person. - Come on, Buck!
一个疯子在胡言乱语 拜旗，难老区
Your kid went and scared us all half to death!
你儿子把大家嘛得站死
Well, what can I tell you, folks, my son,
大采儿，你们也知道我儿子凡
you know... Kids do crazy stuff. You have kids. It's...
小孩子鳃是会做出傻事 你们都有小孩…
No, Dad. It wasn't an acorn.
和爸，那不是橡树果
It was... it was a piece of the sky. Really, it was.
那是…那是一活天空 我是说真的
You gotta believe me.
你一定要相信我
A movie. A movie.
电影，电影耶
They're makin' a movie.
他们要拍一部电影
When? When will everybody forget your big mistake?
天啊 大家每时会总记那件炉事 ?
First it was all over the papers, then they wrote a book about it,
先是报纸一直窜追猛打 和后来有人写了一本韦
then the book on tape, then the board game,
然后又出了有声记 还有棋盘羞戏
the spoons with your face on it...
还在坟是上面印上你的脸
.. the Web site, the commemorative plates.
还有官方网站、纪念资盘
- You saw them, right? - lsaw them.
你也看到了，对吧? 对
Can't eat off 'em.
根本就不能用来吃饭 也不能放进微波炉
- They're not microwave-safe. - You saw the billboards?
你看到广告看板吗 ?
l saw them.
看到了
There's a bumper sticker. I knew it was only a matter of time.
连汽车贴纸都有了 我就知道还早会出汽车贴纸
Billboards I could live with. Posters I could even live with.
广告看板我能接受 甚至过海报我都能接受
But a bumper sticker. It's... it's like glued on forever.
不通汽车贴纸就… 一贴上去就永速撕不下来
It doesn't matter. You know why? Because I've got a plan.
这不重要，你知道高什么吗 ? 因为我有个计划
Yeah, about that. Well, remember how I told you
是啊，关於这件事 记得我跟你说遇
it would be better for you to lay low,
你最好要保持低调
don't call attention to yourself?
画量不要引人注意吐?
- Yes, but I... - See, it's like a game.
记得，可是我… 这就像一种闭戏
Yeah, a game of hide-and-seek, except the goal is never to be found, ever!
没错，提迷城游戏 只是你永速都不要被捉到
Great! Now, we've got a plan, right?
太好了，这才是最好的计划
I'll see ya later! Remember, lay low.
回头见唾 记住哦，保持低调
Yeah. OK.
好啦，知道了
Bye.
拜了
Look, Mama! There's the crazy chicken!
妈，看 是那焦发疯的小蕉
Yes, itis! Crazy chicken. You're so smart. We don't make eye contact. Bye!
没错，就是他，你真鸡明 不要看他，和拜拜
That's it. Today is a new day.
我受多了，今天是菜新的一天
It was a recipe for disaster
这注定是场大英准
A four-course meal of "No sirree"
绝对不会有好嫩果
It seemed that happily ever after
大家都在盯著我看
Was happy everyone was after me
看我怎广再度若神
it was a cup of good intentions
我本来想帮助大家
A tablespoon of one big mess
钻果搞得双飞狗跳
A dash of overreaction
害大家都受到敬哇
And I assume you know the rest
和后来的事你也知道
One little slip
一个小小的错误
It was a fusion of confusion
我的个性迷灯
I guess I probably took the wrong direction
大家都党得我有点和白目
! took a right turn at confusion
恕是分不清东南西北
A left when I should've gone straight on through
而且每炎运气都很背
! ran ahead with my assumptions
不顾一切往前秆
And we all know what that can do
把自己撞得很痛
One little slip
一个小小的错误
It was a fusion of confusion
我的个性迷灯
! get the feeling in this town I'll never live ‘till live down
在这小镇永速混不下去
The one mistake that seems to follow me around
除非克服那个天大错误
But they'll forget about the sky When they aif realize
让大家忘记那件炉事
This guy's about to try to learn to fly
我会一疏溃天
Or hit the ground
或是跌入耸底
How's it going?
你好吗 ?
it was a cup of good intentions
我本来想帮助大家
A tablespoon of one big mess
钻果搞得双飞狗跳
A dash of overreaction
害大家都受到敬哇
And I assume you know the rest
和后来的事你也知道
One little slip
一个小小的错误 (橡果赂加油 )
lt was a humble little stumble
我的个性迷灯
It was a fusion of confusion with a few confounding things
我的个性迷糊、热心度
Very well. Foxy Loxy.
开始点名，狐狸精
- Present, pretty and punctual. - Goosey Loosey.
到 ! 又漂亮又准时 ! 露西狼
Master Runt of the Litter.
乳猪小少答
Present and accounted for, Mr. Woolensworth.
我在这和里，昱只羊老师
Dropped my pencil!
我的锁笔掉了
- Loser! - Henny Penny.
和猪头 哈妮母蕉
- Here. - Ducky Lucky.
到 幸运榴
- Here. - Morkubine Porcupine.
毛奇豪猪
- Yo. - Fish Out of Water.
有 泡泡头急干
Quite. Abby Mallard.
真是的，鸣比野鸣
Ugly duckling.
梗小鸣
Class! I will not tolerate rude behavior
同学们 不准你们这广没礼貌
- at the expense of a fellow... - Hey, no worries, Mr. Woolensworth.
嘲笑别的同学 没关像，叭只羊老绩
You mustn't sneak up on me, Ugly... Abby.
列突然冒出来嘛我 梗…鸣比
- Where was I? - Ugly duckling.
我点名点到谁? 梗小鸣
Oh, yes.
没错
Chicken Little.
四限蕉革
- Tardy again.
他又膛到了 又膛到了
Class, turn to page 62 and translate each word in Mutton.
同学们，翻到62页 把每个生字翻译成羊语
He.
他
She.
她
They.
他们
We.
我们
OK, everyone. Listen up!
各位同学匠好了
I don't wanna hear any quacks, tweets, oinks, whinnies
我不想匠到你们发出 啤哌叫、咕吐叫的声音
or cocklee-doodle-doos when I say... dodgeball.
我们要玩…躲避球
Oh, man.
惨了
Pump it up! Pump it, pump it, pump it!
加油加油加油
Split into two teams. Popular versus unpopular.
大家分成坪队比赛 受霓迎的对抗不受数迎的
- Coach? - Yeah, unpopular?
教绿 什笨事，不受雪迎的?
Shouldn't we review safety guidelines?
先讲讲敌戏规则，好吐?
Sure! Hit the pig, kids!
好啊，集中火力猛K乳和猪
Look out!
小心
Calm down, Runt. Just...
不要怕，乳和猪
Just do what Fish is doing.
学急干那样
- Tough morning? - Arun-in with my old nemesis.
今天很误，对吧 ? 我碰到我的死对头
- Gum in the crosswalk? - He won.
斑马线上的口香糖 ? 这灵他赢了
Your old foe!
你的宿珊
- Incoming on your right. - Thank you.
右侧有球来闵 多府葡告
Yeah, I heard about the movie. Tough break.
我孤说他们要拍电影 你真是倒桩
- Yeah. - Maybe it'll just go straight to video.
是啊 搞不好会直接出多影带
That's the least of my problems.
那和还是小问题
This morning... this morning my dad told me I should basically disappear.
今天早上我老和区 基本上叫我从人间蒸发
But that's not gonna get me down.
但是我不会因此而气侯
I've got a plan. You want to hear about it?
我有一个计划，人想黄吗?
No, no, no! this one's good.
别人这榜，这个计划超训的
Look, one moment destroyed my life, right? One moment.
那一刻角了我一生
- Warthog at 3:00! - lsee him!
三点甸方向有将猪 我看到了
- Yes! - So I figure all l need is a chance...
好耶 我只要一个机会
All l need is a chance to do something great
我只要一个机会做出大事
to make everyone forget the "sky falling" thing once and for all.
大家就会忘记 天空掉下来的那件粮事
Then my dad'll finally have a reason to be proud of me.
我从也会终认以我高芝
Time out!
斩停
Nurse!
访士
- Hi, Tiffany! - Hey, man, what's goin' on?
嗨，晓芬 叶，有什么事 ?
So, what do you think?
你觉得怎榜 ?
OK, listen.
好吧，匠我说
You said the sky was falling.
你说天空掉下来了
- Your dad didn't support you. el.
你和区没有支持你
And you have been hurting inside ever since, right?
你一直觉得 内心受到伤害，对吧?
- It's hurt. It stung. OK? - It's hurt, but... Yes.
很心痛 是很痛，没错
- That's the nutshell. - Yes, but...
就是这广回事 没错，可是…
- No.. - But, it's...
别否认 不遇那是…
What's got to happen now is the nut needs to be cracked open.
你一定要快刀新乱麻面对问题
And not one little chip at a time, but... bam!
而且绝对不能拖泥带水
Smash! Bits of emotion flying everywhere! Anger! Frustration!
把你的情绪都爆出来 愤怒、挫折
Denial! Fear! Deep depression, in fact! You see what I'm saying?
自我否定、恐眉、温串 你懂我的意思吗 ?
All right, forget the nut part. Here's the main thing.
忘了我刚才说的着 我要说的重点是
You have got to stop messing around, and deal with the problem.
你不能一直逃避 要勇敢去面对问题
- But... - Here's the real solution.
可是… 这才是解决办法
You and your dad talk-talk-talking... closure!
你跟你和爸要把事情讲开来 有一个圆满结局
- Closure? - Closure,
周满寻局 ? 没错
talking about something until it's resolved.
靠谈心来解决问题
Wait! Hold on! See? Look.
等一下，我给你看 看到没 ?
There's a whole section about it in this month's Modern Mallard.
这个月的「野鸣时尚] 正好有专题报于
- Incredibly appropriate! - [ told you, I have a plan.
太送合你了 ! 我说遇，我有一个计划
Yeah, but according to Cosmo Duck,
[柯萝风丹」 也说
you should "stop the squawk and try the talk."
「 列再听吃叫，好好恋一谈]
Beautiful Duckling says,
「美恒佳人1」 说
"Avoiding closure with your parents can cause early molting."
「 事情没有圆满辣局 就会提早脱毛1
See? Closure.
凡事都要有圆满结局
Come on, repeat after me. You, your dad, talk-talk...
来，跟我说一遍 你要找你和爸谈心
Abby, Abby, Abby, listen! Talking's a waste of time.
鸣比，贡我说 谈心只是浪费时间
I got to do something great so my dad doesn't think I'm a loser.
我只要做件大事 我爸就不会觉得我是避脚
Come on. You are not a loser.
拜旗，你才不是避脚
You're inventive and resourceful and funny and cute and...
你是个点子王 隐明搞笑的小钙哥
What?
什么 ?
Yeah... Runt!
这个咏…乳猪
Should Chicken Little have a good talk with his dad and clear the air
难丁是不是应该 和他多把事情讲并来
or keep searching for Band-Aid solutions and never deal with the problem?
还是用OK钢把伤口放起来 不去面对问题 ?
Band-Aid solutions!
用OK网诞伤口
- Runt! - Well, I'm sorry!
乳和猪 ! 对不起
I'm very bad at reading facial cues.
我很不会察言观色
Fish, help me out here.
急干，旭帮忙
Men.
男生都一样
‘Twas beauty that killed the beast.
都是美女害死了野葡
I guess only girls are good at honest communication and sensitivity.
我猜只有女生 才能诚不又感性地江通
That does it! We were in a time-out, Foxy!
我忍夭可忍了 教张喊暂停耶，狐狸精
Prepare to hurt. And I don't mean emotionally, like I do.
不是只有我心理受创…
We will save you!
我们会去救你
Fall back! Mad goose!
快逃呀，他抓狂了
Chicken Little!
难丁!
picking fights in gym class and the fire alarm?
上朵育课打架阐事 还扔动火警警报
Ever since that "sky falling" incident, he's been nothing but trouble!
自从天空掉下来那件事 他就不断在车麻烦
Now look, Buck.
职我说，难老区
You know I have the utmost respect for you.
你知道我很尊敬你
I mean, you were Buck "Ace" Cluck,
你曾经是英雄卡拉蕉
our school baseball star.
棒球校队的明星球员
But let's face the facts.
不明咱们要承认事实
Your kid, he's nothing like you at all.
有其父不一定必有其予
OK.
好吧
Thank you for talking to me. I'll take care of my son.
谢谢你告诉我这件事 我会把我儿子管好
I... Dad, it wasn't my fault.
和爸，那不是我的错
- It was Foxy. She's always... - All right. It's fine.
都是狐狸精，她每灾都… 没关人和你
You don't have to explain anything.
你什么都不用解释
Hey, Dad?
邓
I was thinkin’. Yeah, what if I...?
我在想哦，如果我…
What if...?
如果我…
What if I joined the baseball team?
如果我加入棒球除
Hey, why don't you watch where you're going?!
咀，开车要看路
Sorry, there, buddy! Sorry, sorry.
抱娄，老兄，对不起
Baseball? Son, we talked about this.
棒球 ? 儿子，我们谈遇这件事
Yeah, right. But, you know, that was when I was small.
是啊，不过那时候我还很小
I put on five ounces this year. I've really bulked up.
今年我重了五瘟斯 变得真的很壮
Really, son? Baseball. Are you sure?
真的吗 ? 你真的想打棒球 ?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I mean, you know, hey, why not, right?
真的啊，和为什么不行呢?
- Yeah, why not, but why? - Well, Dad,
可是你为什么要打呢 ? 因为各
you were such a big baseball star in high school.
你以前是棒球校队明星球员
You could give me some pointers.
可以教我一些读硅
But son, I'm just wondering...
儿子，我在想
Maybe baseball isn't exactly your thing, you know?
也许你不通合打棒球
Have you considered the chess team or the glee club?
你有汽有考虑遇 西洋棋社或是合唱团?
And some teenagers, you know, they get quite a rush from stamp collecting.
有些青少年收集邮票 也收集得很开心
- No. - Wanna stop? We'll get stamps.
不要啦 你想停车下去买邮票吗 ?
- [don't like stamps. - Colors, colorful things...
我不喜数邮票 地票很漂亮耶
No, I was thinkin’ baseball!
不，我只想打棒球
I can't wait to see the look on your face
等我打出一支“蓝”不让
when I smack that ball in for a touchdown!
你一定会很高导
Dad... I'm kidding.
和爸，我是在开玩笑啦
That was a... that was a joke.
那是个冷笑话
Just do me one favor, son.
者我一个已，儿子
Why, sure, Dad. Anything.
好啊，没问题
Just please try not to get your hopes too high.
你千莲不要期望太高
Yeah, but Dad, I mean, I...
不明和爸，我很认真耶
I mean, I think I can...
我真的可以…
OK, Dad.
好吧，和区
! bruise you
我伤你的心
You bruise me
你也伤我的心
We both bruise so
我们都在货彼此的心
Easily
直接伤征此的心
Too easily
杀不肯玛易
To let it show
流露真感情
I love you
我爱你
And that's alf 1 know
就这广简量
Oh, Chloe. If only you were here.
可邓，如果逮在就好了
You'd know what to do.
人一定知道该怎广做
And all my plans
我的理想计划
Keep fallin’ through
全都把法实现
Depend on you
全都靠你成真
To help them grow
者我成长
I love you
我爱你
- That's my boy! - Gee, thanks, Dad!
我的儿子好棒哦 谢了，和区
And that's alf
就这广简量
It's really alll know
我爱你
It's alll know
我只知道这广多
Come on. All l need is a chance.
拜旗，我只需要一个机会
It's all
我只知道
I know
我爱你
I'm not gonna take it anymore
(狐狸钴大多全腾)
! got to shake it up now
(我们的英雄，狐狸精)
I'm not gonna take it no more
(小橡队今天事春名和冠军)
Lean to the left Lean to the right
向堪看、向右看
C'mon Acorns Fight, fight, fight! Go, Acorns!
橡果朵生街和 加油 ? 攀果降
There's excitement in the air, ladies and gentlemen.
各位先生女士 空气中汪漫著愉备气息
It's been two decades since Oakey Oaks has beaten rivals
二十年来没出败过死对头
the Spud Valley Taters.
洋苹头洋苹队
Down by only a single run, with a player in scoring position,
橡果降现在只落后一分 有一人在得分位置
we have a chance.
(比数14比13)
This excitement isn't about the fun of baseball, the prize.
最让大家兴奋的 不是棒球本身或是赢球
It's about the gloating and rubbing their noses in it,
而是赢球和后 得意洋洋地向对手哈融
the "Nah-nah-na-na-na! We beat you!" taunting
在他们面前说
- that comes with the winning. - Yeah!
「 咱们打赢你们了1 好耶
That's right. Oakey Oaks and Mayor Turkey Lurkey
没错，橡果镇的火镇长 和全体镇民
will finally have bragging rights again for one full year!
就可以自吹自播一整年
This battle has taken a heavy toll on our hometown heroes.
但是这场比赛也让 咱们的球员季疫力囊
After nine grueling innings and several players out with injuries,
打了九局之后 有好比名球员受伤
the Acorns are scraping the bottom of the roster.
橡果降只好派出板王球员
Hopefully, there's just enough muscle on the bench to pull out a win.
只希望他们能帮球降赢得比赛
Up next... Chicken Little.
接下来的打者是…难丁
Clearly a long shot, folks.
这是不可能的任务
Little hasn't been up to bat once since joining the team.
难丁加入球降和后 从来没有出场打击
- He's gonna lose the game for us! - But wait!
他会害球队输球 且慢
If he can just get a walk and advance to first, that powerhouse,
他只要被四束球 保送上一坚就能让
Foxy Loxy can step up and save us all.
…强棒狐狸精 施展威力、挽回劣势
She's had a terrific game so far. A shoo-in for the MVP trophy.
她的表现太精采了 肯定会成为最有价值球员
OK, kid, listen up.
小鬼，匠好了
You have an itty-bitty, teeny-tiny strike zone.
你的好球带非常小
There's no way he can throw you out! Take the walk. Don't swing.
他不可能把你三振 别挥棒，等著被保送
- [have a good feeling... - Look at me. Don't swing.
我很有信心… 看著我，别挥棒
Take the walk. You hear me? Just take the walk!
等著被保送，册到没 ?
- But, coach, wait! - Don't swing!
可是教鳞，等等 千菌别挥棒
Nervous, gangly, barely able to hold the pine, Little advances to the box.
瘦小的蕉丁连球棒都拿不动 他紧张地向打萤区走去
He's going to bat from the right.
他要和从右亲打贡
Make it the left. No, the right.
他要和从左尊打贡 不对，是右遵
- The right. - Easy out!
右亲 他和背定出局
Looks like left field's found something better to do,
左外野手老神在在做别的事
center field's got a hunger pang in his second stomach
中外野手开始吃起草来
- and right field's digging for grubs. - Play ball!
右外野手则在控蝗划 打球
Why him? Why now?
怎麻是他 ? 怎庆玩这一刻?
l won't embarrass you, Dad. Not this time.
和爸，这我不会让你和脸
Here's the wind-up, the pitch! It's a high cutter.
投手投出第一球 这是高桥球
Ball!
壤球
Strike one!
一好球
I'm not going to sugarcoat it. I've seen roadkill with faster reflexes.
我要实话实说 我没见遇反应这广慢的球员
The catcher lays down the signals. Here's the pitch.
捕手打出信咏，投手投球
Curve ball low and outside, he swings!
这是一个外角变化球，他挥棒
Strike two!
十好球
I said, don't swing!
我叫你不要挥棒
Don't swing!
别挥棒
- No! - Batter up!
不要 准备打击
Two in the hole!
连续十个好球
One more strike, it's a punch out, folks, and we're all going home.
再一个好球 咱们就得垂头吕气地回家
Today is a new day.
今天是声新的一天
Don't swing!
别挥棒
Well, take away my squeaky toy! It's a hit!
我不敢相信，这是一支安打
- Ahit?
安打?
But wait! The batter is still at home plate.
且慢，打者膛站在本村
He's standing in a daze. Run, kid, run!
他采掉了 快跑村呀，小旬
Go, son! Run! Run!
儿子，快跑呀
There he goes, headed the wrong way.
他并始跑了，他跑错方向了
- Wait, wait, wait! - No, no! Not that way!
等等 不是那焉，是另一遵
- Run the other way! - Turn around!
往另一天跑 快掉头
Wait, wait! He's turned! I've never said these words before,
等等，他掉头了 我不敢相信我会这广说
but he's actually rounding home plate!
不通他真的又跑到本村
- Goosey Loosey steps on home... - Today's a new day!
露西狼奔回本杰 今天是声新的一天
We have a tie game! They're scrambling in the alley.
我们打成平手了 他们都街到外野
Looks like Rodriguez has it. Nope, it's the center fielder!
右外野手拿到球 不对，是中外野手
Mayhem in the outfield, as Rodriguez is fired to second.
外野一片混乱 右外野手被于到二村
Catch is complete, but where's the ball?
他被二村手接住，但是球啊 ?
Little touches the bag and keeps going. A hunt for the rock.
难丁继续跑桂，对手继续找球
The fielders are having trouble. Commotion out there!
对方球员手忙脚乱 场面一片混乱
- It's stuck! It's stuck! - Tip the cow!
球被卡住了 咱们来网牛吧
It's the old tip-the-cow play.
他们使出网牛那一招
The kid heads for the hot corner, a stand-up triple!
他向三柑直街遇去
- Yes! - Hold up! No!
好耶 等等，不!
He's going for the whole enchilada!
他要奔回本村
The ball of wax, kit and the caboodle!
打出一支红不让
Go back! You're never gonna make it!
快回去，你会被刺杀出局
He's trying to lighten his load!
难丁想减轻重量
The outfield behind, Little's on all cylinders!
他使出吃奶的力量狂奔
He slides for the dish!
他温进本杰
It's going to be a photo finish at home!
看来会成功
You're out!
出局
Oh, folks. Folks, what a heartbreaker.
各位，这真是令人伤心欲绝
- Wait! - Wait, wait!
等等 等一下
Wait a cotton-picking second. Hold your horses, here,
先别急，别气侯
and horses hold your breath. This might not be over. He...
选有希望，我们迁有机会
He's...
他…-
Safe! The runner is safe!
安全，打者安全奔回本村
It's all over, folks! The Acorns have done the impossible!
我们赢了 橡果降完成不可能的任务
For the first time in 20 years, we won the pennant!
我们二十年来第一炎赢得冠军
Mothers, kiss your babies! You've witnessed a miracle!
我的老天，这真是一个奇踊
Remember where you were at this moment. The smells! The sounds!
大家记住这大史性的一刻 膀利的气息和娄呼志
There's a new winner in town and his name is Chicken Little!
今天出了一个新的英雄 他的名字就是共丁
That was just a lucky hit!
他只是走狗屎运
Yes, Chicken Little, it's all yours!
难丁，你出运了
The victory, the triumph, the glory!
膀利的森耀全都属於他
And getting doused with a sticky drink that soaks into your undies
他全身也会被个满还动饮料
and chafes for hours!
内裤被浸温超难受的
This is one memory you'll savor forever!
这是令人永生难忘的回居
Yeah!
好耶
Yes, yes, yes! We won! We won! That's my boy out there!
好耶，我们赢了 那是我儿子
That's my boy!
我的好孩子
lam the champion, my friend
我是冠军，朋友
And I'll keep on fightin’ till the end
我将奋同到永速
lam the champion
我是冠军
‘Cause lam the champion
因为我是全世界
Of the world
…的冠军
Here's the wind-up and the pitch!
投手拿起球，用力投出
- Aknuckleball! - He swings!
中间方向的慢速爸化球 打者挥棒
- Crack! - It's going.
棒耶 这是一支安打
- He rounds first, to second! - It hits high off the wall!
他先跑到一坚再衙向二村 球被打到外轰蒜上
He flies past third and heads for the plate!
他踩了三树和后直奔本杰
It's a scramble for the ball! It's gonna be close!
球被于回本柑，情况危急
He is safe!
他安全了
- The mighty Acorns win! - Yes! Acorns win!
伟大的橡果降赢了 ! 橡果降赢了 !
Geez, you know,
你知道吗 ?
I guess that puts the whole "sky is falling" incident
我猜这下我们终尖可以忘了
behind us once and for all. Hey, kiddo?
…天空掉下来那件粮事 对吧，儿子?
You bet, Dad.
那是一定的啦，和区
Unless you think we need... closure?
除非我们需要圆满结局
Closure? What's to close here?
周满寻局 ? 这寻局已经很周满了
Unless you think we need to close...
除非你觉得我们需要…
- Not me. - It's closed!
不用 没事了
- lagree. Vacuum sealed. - Shut tight!
那就不用再提了 永速不用再提
OK, great, Dad. You... Closure, I dunno.
太好了，一切都OK 不需要什么圆满结局
All right. Enough fun.
好了，玩级了
Good talk. Good talk, son.
咱们父子傅聊得很愉快
- Here, I'll give you a push. - Rock me a little. Help me.
我推你一把 稍微拘我一下
- OK. - OK, I'm up.
好了 我起来了
Hey.
哩
Good night, Ace.
晚安，英雄
Here's the wind-up... and the pitch!
投手拿起球，用力投出
Thanks.
谢啦
Thanks for the chance.
多训你给我这个机会
No!
不 !
A piece of the sky?! Shaped like a stop sign?! Not again!
一浙天空?像交通标读? 又来了
Hey! Son! You all right? I'm coming!
儿子，你没事吧 ? 我来了
I'm coming! I'm comin’ upstairs!
我来了，我马上来
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
出了什么事 ? 没事
You sure? I thought I heard you yell.
真的吗 ?我孤到你大叫
No.
没啦
I fell out of bed.
我只是不小心掉下床
- How'd you get over there? - Over where?
你怎广会掉到那里 ? 哪里 ?
- There. There! - Where?
那里呀
How'd you get over there?
你怎广会掉到那里 ?
Who're we talking about?
我们在说谁呀?
Never mind. What's the difference? Look, the past is behind us, right?
算了，这不重要 遇去的事都遇去了
Tomorrow's gonna be a new day.
明天是菜新的一天
Please be gone, please be gone, please be gone...
拜旗你消失不见…
Good.
太好了
No.
不
I gotta call Abby!
我得打给鸭比
Yo, I'if tell you what I want What I really really want
我告诉你，我想要什千
Tell me what you want What you really really want
你告诉我，你想要什么
Really really really wanna zigazig ah
我要这个这个那个那个
If you wanna be my lover You gotta get with my friends
想当我的情人，就对我朋友好
- Gotta get with my friends - Make it last forever
对我的朋友好 大家一起当
Friendship never ends If you wanna be my lover
…永下的好朋友 想当我的情人
You have got to give Taking is too easy
…就要付出真心 不能呈方面接受
- But that's the way it is - Hello! Mallard residence.
事情就是这样 喂，鸣比家
Tell you what I want
我告诉你我想要什么
Runt! Quiet! I'm on the phone!
乳猪，安静，我在讲电话
- l wanna really... - Runt!
乳和猪 !
Hey! Where are you?
嗨，你在哪儿 ?
- We already started. We were just... - lt opened up!
我们都并唱了 天又塌下来
What?!
什么 ?
All right, guys. Watch this.
大采儿，看好唾
Bizarre.
超怪的
OK. Lemme guess. You haven't told your dad yet.
好吧，让我猜 你膛没告诉你和爷
- Well... - [knew it!
这个嘛… 我就知道
Why haven't you told him? There hasn't been
你贺什么不告诉他 ? 因为你中你区
- "you, your dad, talk-talk-talking." - There was talking.
…根本就没有谈心 我们有谈心呀
- There was definitely talking. - Really? What did he say?
我们谈了很多耶 真的吗 ? 他说什么 ?
What?
什么 ?
All right, that's it. We are doing an intervention!
不行，我受金了 我们要插手管这件事
You have got to stop messing around and deal with the problem!
你不能再拖拖拉拉 赶快面对问题
- She's right! - Abby, please.
她说得对 风比，拜旗
This is what fell on me the first time.
我上灵就是被这玩意K到闫
There's no way I'm bringing this up again.
打死我也不会再跟他说
- No, he's not. - Runt!
他死都不会说 乳猪
Sorry! I'm a gutless flip-flopper.
抱娄，我是没种的炉头草
OK. I'm sure there's a simple, logical explanation.
这一定有很简章 很符合须辑的解释
I mean, it could be a piece of weather balloon,
这可能是气象球
or maybe it's part of some experimental communications satellite.
或是实验人造卫星的零件
I don't care. I want it out of my life, gone for good.
不管是什科 我都要它从我的生命中消失
Everything back to normal.
让一切恢复正常
Hey, remember when that icy blue stuff fell from the sky?
记得上次有一根 蓝色冰柱从空而降吗 ?
Everybody thought it was from space and stuff?
大家都以为来自外太空
And it just turned out to be frozen pee from a jet airplane.
钻果是来自喷射客机的小便
Yeah, that's right. It's frozen pee.
没错，是冰阑的小便
Yeah. It's frozen pee. Pee, pee, pee, pee pee.
冰冻的小便，小便小便
- Could you stop saying that? - What? Pee?
拜旗你列再说了 什么 ? 小便?
- Pee. - Tinkle?
小便 小发呢 ?
- Piddle? Wee-wee? - Whiz?
尿尿啊 ? 吹哮?
OK, subject change.
改释话题，好响 ?
- Make pishee? - [don't care what it is!
上一吐 我才不管它是什么
Are you gonna help me get rid of it or not?
快划我把它弄走
Flying Fish! Take cover!
飞和急 ! 快六 !
Fish!
和急干!
- No! - Fish!
不 !
Come on, come on, come on!
快点，快点
Wait, wait, whoa, son! Where's the fire here?
慢点，儿子，失火了吐?
Chicken Little has something to tell you! Tell him. He can handle it.
难丁有话要跟你说 快说呀，他能接受啦
Who're we talkin’ about?
我们在说谁呀?
Gotta go, Dad! Bye!
我得走了，拜了
You got to be ready to listen to your children,
父母要随时准备 倾匠孩子的心志
even if they have nothing to say.
即使他们没什么好说的
- Sit tight, Fish! - Fish! We will try to save you!
坐好了，惫干 和急干，我们会来救你
I'm sorry! Wait!
对不起，等等我
Sorry!
对不起
Curb!
小心
Fish!
和急干!
Abby!
鸭比!
Abby! Wake up!
鸣比，快醒醒 !
Come on! Let's get outta here!
来吧，咱们快走
Oh, poor Fish!
可情的和急干
He's probably stuffed and mounted like an intergalactic trophy or...
他不是被做成标本持起来
..maybe he's a half-living host implanted with face-hugging babies.
就是被植入到外星实守里面 变得半死不活
One thing's for sure, man. He's gone!
我只知道一件事，他持了
- Gone, man! - Not yet!
他死定了 还没有
Oh, snap.
惨了
Fish.
急干
Hey! What are you doing? Come on!
你在干癖?快来啦
Where are you, Fish?!
和急干，你在哪里?
I can't handle the pressure! Go on without me!
我受不了压力，你们去吧
- Runt. - You're just fine.
乳猪 你不会有事的
I'll jeopardize the mission! Endanger us all!
我会拖累你们，危害这项任务
Throw me overboard while you still have a chance!
趁还来得及把我坡下去吧
Just leave me some ammo, little water, some chips if you have ‘em.
给我一点弹药，一点水 有的话顺便给我一些暮片
Calm. OK, all right. Listen.
冷静点，没事的
- Where's your bag? - Everything's OK.
你的纸袋呢? 不会有事的
- Now breathe. - Breathe.
呼吸
- No, slowly. - Slowly.
等等，慢慢来 慢慢来
OK. Now, just do the thing you do to relax.
现在 使出让你放胡的那一招
Well, you can tell by the way
我走路的样子一看就知道
l use my walk I'm a woman's man
我是少女般手
No time to talk
没时间理你
Stayin’ alive, stayin’ alive’
我要活下去，我要活下去
Fish!
和急干!
Fish! Are you OK?
和急干，你没事吧 ?
Did they hurt you? Say something!
你有没有受伤 ? 快说话呀
Don't tap the glass. They hate it when you do that.
列鼓玻璃，和刍最讨厥这样
All right, let's get out of here. Where's Runt?
咱们快闪吧，乳猪呢?
We're next.
接下来是地球
Run!
快跑!
OK! That's it!
好了，我决定了
We're running back to your house. Tell your dad!
我们要跑回你家 把这件事告诉你区
OK! You're right, you're right!
好啦，说得对
Stayin’ alive, stayin’ alive
我要活下去，我要活下去
Stayin’ alive
我要活下去
Oh, Runt!
乳猪
Push! Push! No!
用力推，不!
- Runt! - No! Not pull! Push!
乳和猪 ! 不是拉，用力推
We gotta get outta here right now! Come on...
我们得赶快内人 快来呀
No! Come on, you guys! Hu...
不 ! 大影多，快点
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
快点…快点…
OK, time out!
暂停一下
So... have you been to the mall?
你们有洛有去大喜场 ?
Come on, buddy.
快归，加油
I'm sorry.
对不起
Tension makes me bloat.
我一紧张就会水膝
Come on, guys! Hurry, hurry, hurry!
来吧，快点…快点…
Look out!
小心了
Thanks! Curse these genetically tiny legs!
谢了 可恶，和猪天生就是小及
What's that noise?
那是什么声音 ?
Sorry. Nervous eater.
抱娄，我一紧张就会狂吃
- Run! - Wait! Fish!
快跑 等等，和急干
The school bell! We've got to ring the school bell to warn everyone!
校甸 ! 我们得鼓校钾警告大家
Come on!
来吧
Hurry! Hurry!
快，快
Go! Go!
快走，快走
It's locked!
校门锁住了
They're... they're comin’.
他们…他们来了
I need a soda.
我需要一逝汽水
Come on, buddy. Come on, buddy!
快点…快点…
- The corner's wrinkled! - Why are we doing this?
这张人钞票太敏了 干桨要买汽水呀?
Come on, take it, take it!
快进去
Yes!
好耶
Come on! Work! Work!
快点，给我汽水 !
Work! You work!
给我汽水 !
What happened? I blacked out there for a second.
发生什么事 ? 我暂时失去了知觉
The sky is falling!
天空掉下来了，天空掉下来了
It was just an acorn. A little acorn!
这只是一颗小橡桂果
I can't tell you how embarrassed I am, folks.
大彩儿，我也党得很坪脸
Ring the bell!
快鼓甸
Come on, Chicken Little!
快点，难丁，快敲甸
What?
什么 ?
Let's check the weather with Riz.
接下来是天气预报
A cold front is moving in so...
冷妖正在接近，所以…
The alarm bell has been activated! Quick! Get a camera crew!
有人敲警甸 快派SNG车做连线报半
Chicken Little! You better have a good explanation for this!
难丁，你最好解释清楚
There's, there's... It's a... You have to... D'oh! Doo wah!
有…是…你们要…
What did he say?
他说什么 ?
Follow me! Come on! Hurry! Hurry! Aliens here!
跟我来，来呀 快点，外星人入优
Aliens here!
外星人入侵地球
It's... it's happening again.
他又郁运了
Come on! Hurry! Hurry!
快来呀，快点
Come on. Come on. You're about to see it!
快来呀，就快看到了
Quick! Quick! It's taking off!
快点，它要升空了
Come on! If you don't hurry, you're gonna miss it!
你们不快点就会错遇的
Oh, look! A penny!
瞧，一帮硬殖
- Guys! - Oh, right.
大影儿 对哦
Hurry! Hurry!
快点，快点
Come on! Quick! It's taking off!
快点，它就快升空了
Come on! Hurry up! Please! It's right in...
拜旗你们快点，它就在…
- What are we lookin’ for? - [don't know.
我们在看什么呀? 我也不知道
Yeah. OK. I know this looks bad,
我知道这匠起来很扯
but there's an invisible spaceship right there
不遇那儿有一和架隐形赤碟
with aliens who are here to invade Earth!
上面的外星人要入侵地球
Let me show you.
我证明给你们看
Bad throw.
生得好灶哦
OK, let me try again.
我再斌一遍
- Bad throw. - We all know I don't have a good arm,
超避的 大家都知道我力气很小
but there's these cloaking panels on the bottom.
不遇飞碟底下有隐形板
They make it disappear. One fell out of the sky and hit me right on the head.
它们可以消失不网 有一浙从天空掉下来K到我
It's the acorn thing all over again.
又是橡符果那件春事
There's no story here.
没有和佑动的新闻
At least we can sell the video to Chickens Gone Wild.
至少这些片段能误给 [娄笑一对管]
- I'm telling ya, it was here! - No, wait! There were aliens!
等等，真的有外星人
It's true! They had eyes... They're glowing and then tentacles!
他们有发亮的眼睛和触角
And maps with planets with X's through them!
而且在星球上面打了又
Runt, that's enough!
乳猪，角了
Don't make Mommy take away your Streisand collection!
别逼我拿走你的 芭芭拉史以珊CD收藏
Mom? You leave Barbra out of this!
妈，这不关她的事
Why can't you keep that child of yours under control?
你贺什么连自己的小孩 都管不好 ?
- What kind of parent are you? - Everybody, I'm telling the truth.
你这和苞和苞是怎广当的? 我说的是实话
Dad! Dad! I'm not making this up!
和爸，答，我不是频儿的
You gotta believe me this time.
你这次一定要相信我
No, son. I don't.
不，儿子，我不相信你
I can't tell you how embarrassed I am, folks.
大彩儿，我也党得很坪脸
Looks like this is just
看来这只是
a big, crazy misunderstanding.
…一场天大的误会
Well, other than the penny, this whole evening was a wash!
除了抢到袋，我是白跑一趟
Mr. Cluck, don't take it so hard. No one blames you.
难老和爸，别这广自责 浊有人会怪你
Emergency, emergency! Send help!
紧急状况，请派出支援
Reports of panic and mayhem . . are pouring in
难丁昨晚又西灾
after yet another Chicken Little incident last night.
再度引起恐慌和混乱
In one instance, a family of lemmings was sent running in fear,
有一家子旅鼠被嘛到想自杀
but unable to find a cliff, they instead began throwing themselves
但是印找不到悬崖可跳 藉是全家大小都从
- from the nearest park bench. - Hello? I'm sorry.
…公园板枉跳下来 咀?抱娄
Hello? I apologize. Hello? Give me break! Hello?
咀?对不起 拜旗傍了我吧
What? You were trampled? That's terrible.
什么 ? 你被踩到 ? 真可怕
I thought rabbits' feet were supposed to be lucky.
我以贺锡子脚是幸到符
You have hate mail.
您有优恨邮件
- I'm truly sorry. That wasn't funny. - You have more hate mail.
很抱菊，那不好笑 您有更多优恨邮件
Hi. What are you saying, sir?
你想说什么 ?
Your hate mail box is full.
您的优恨信箱被塞爆
Oh, yes. I do see the skywriting there.
我看到天空的喷字
Thank goodness the cloud blocked the last letter. Hello?
幸好一芭才遮住最和后一个字
Hey, hey, hey! Watch your mouth. Yeah?
喂，噶巴放乾浮点 是吗?
OK, I love you too, Mom. Bye.
妈，我也爱你，拜了
Hello? Really. Well...
喂?真的吗 ?
If there was ever a time to talk to your dad, it's now.
如果你想对你和区说出真心话 就要趁现在
It's too late for that.
太膛了
It's too late, baby, now it's too late.
太膛了，实忠，太膛了
Though they really did try to make it.
路然他们曾经党试遇
Runt.
乳猪
Just think about it.
你要考虑一下
Something inside has died and they just can't hide
他们的心已区，扰法隐藏
and they just can't fake it. Oh, no, no.
也么法再假装 不 …-不 多
Runt, I just really want to be alone right now.
乳猪，我想一个人静一毅
Abby! Runt! Fish!
鸣比乳猪 ! 急干!
Look! There! Look there! Look there!
你们看，你们看
- What is that thing?! - Look at that!
那是什么东永 ? 你们看
- His name is Kirby? - They left him behind?
他叫北鼻? 他们忘了把他带走?
Darth Vader is Luke's father?
黑武士是路克的老区 ?
No, don't... Come on, come on, don't cry.
不要哭，别哭
We're here for you. We're gonna do whatever it takes to get you back home.
我们会攻你的 我们会想办法送你回家
Here, blow.
来，措鼻涕
OK.
好吧
See, guys? He's cool. He was just freaked out. That's all.
瞧，他很乖 他只是被嘛壤了
Run!
快跑!
Those are your parents?
那是你的和爸苞嫣妈?
And they brought the galactic armada?
他们把银河系稻队带来 ?
- Watch out for the kid! Don't hit him! - There you are. Get in the car.
小心别撞到小朋友 你在这和儿，上车
- [ gotta tell you something. - What?
我得告诉你一件事 什么 ?
I know, I know! You were right! Alien invasion. I see that now.
我知道，你说对了 外星人入公地球，我看到了
- Look up! There it is! - Dad, you know, about that...
抬头看，它们来了 和葡，有关於这件事
- It's actually just a rescue mission. - Rescue mission?
其实这只是救援行动 救援行动 ?
This alien kid was left and they're coming back to get him!
外星人只是回来找小孩
We have to help him, ‘cause if we don't, who else will?
我们得帮他，他只能靠我们
What?!
什么 ?
Forget it. You wouldn't believe me anyway.
算了，反正你不会相信我
Son!
儿子
Son, come back! Son! Chicken Little!
儿子，快回来，难本 !
Mr. Cluck! Wait! He's telling the truth!
难老和爸，他说的是真的
He is! Though, given his track record, we understand why you don't believe him!
没错，不明他信用不好 你不相信，我们也能理解
Is there any sign of him?
找到他了吗?
Negative.
没有
We'll have to send in the ground troops.
我们得派遣地面部队
Watch out for the kid! No! Don't! Don't hit him! Don't hit... Look out!
小心是 别撞到小朋友，小心
Chicken Little!
难丁!
What? Where's your head?
搞什么 ? 你疯啦 ?
We gotta get outta here! Come on! Come o...
我们得赶快逃命，来吧…
- You, with the running and the jumping! - Dad. No, wait.
列再跑来跑去了 不，等等
What are you guys doing? We gotta get outta here!
你们在干癖? 我们得超快逃走
It's like War of the Worlds out there!
这简直就是世界大台
- Stop pulling! - Just listen to me for one second!
不要拉 停下来孤我说
- It's not dangerous! - We are under attack!
他们没有危险 外星人大奉入侵
Will you two stop messing around and deal with the problem?
拜旗你们不要关了 赶快面对问题
- You're never there for me! - What?
你从来都不支持我 什么 ?
OK, that's not what l had in mind, but...
我不是这意思，不通…
You're never there for me. I mean,
你从来都不支持我
you were when I won the game, but not when I thought the sky fell.
我赢了球赛你就支持我 我说天空掉下来你务不相信
And not at the ball field and not now!
你现在也不支持我
This is good! Keep going. Keep going!
这样很好，继续说
You've been ashamed since the acorn thing.
橡桂果事件后 你就觉得我让你很于脸
We have to talk because Modern Mallard says avoiding closure
我们要把话讲并来 因为「野鸣时尚上 就
can lead to molting. I'm already small
没有圆满钻局会提早脱毛 我已经这广瘦小了
and I don't think Il could handle being bald!
要是序头一定会抓狂
I didn't... realize, son.
我花不…知道，儿子
I never meant to...
我兹不是故意…
The acorn, the sky, I mean, the whole...
橡桂果和天空那整件事…
You're right. You're right.
你说得对
Your mom, she was...
你是始，她比较…
You know, she was always good with stuff like this.
她一向都比较会处理这种事
Me...
至於我…
..l'm gonna need a lot of work.
我得更努力学习
But you need to know that I love you,
但是你要知道不管怎样
no matter what.
我都一样爱你
And I'm sorry l....
我也很抱攻
And I'm sorry if l ever made you feel like that was something...
我不该让你觉得你必须…
..you had to earn.
…事到我的爱
And we're good. Let's go. Let's go.
真心话说完了，我们走吧
OK, Dad. Now, all we gotta do is return helpless little Kirby.
好吧，现在我们只要 把可情的北鼻交回去就行
Return this whatever it is?
这是什么东永 ?
This is crazy! Crazy!
这太疯狂了
Crazy wonderful!
这太棒了
- Do you really mean it? - You bet! Anything, son.
你是说真的? 当然吐，儿子
Come on, Dad. We've got a planet to save!
来吧，和多 我们要拯救地球
Crazy supportive. That's me!
我超支持我的小孩
This thing likes to nibble, doesn't it?
这小东西很爱咏人哦
By the way, I'd like to say I've always found you extremely attractive!
对了，我一直都觉得人超美的
Now that's closure.
这才是圆满结局
Wait! Wait! What's goin’ on?!
等等，这是怎广回事 ?
They've given her an alien mind-wipe!
她被外星人洗脑了
OK, son. What do we do now?
儿子，现在怎广办 ?
OK. This is a piece of cake, Dad.
很简单，各
All we have to do is take the kid down the street to the giant metal alien.
只要把这小孩 还给可怕的外星人就行
We surrender! Here! Take the key to the city!
我们投降，请拿走我的市答
Key to my car?
我的车给 ?
Tic Tac?
口香代 ?
Forget plan A!
放率A计划
OK, OK, what now, son?
好了，现在该怎广办 ?
Who, by the way, l support 100 percent.
我百分百支持他
- Plan B? - Of course! Plan B! What is plan B?
B计划 ? 当然唾，B计划是什么 ?
What? You have to go to the bathroom? You want juice?
什么 ? 你要尿原 ? 喝果汁?
A snack? Corn dog on a stick?
吃零食?吃热狗 ?
Want to play some golf? What do you want?!
打高霄夫球 ? 你到底要什么 ?
I stink at this. I'm a horrible father.
我超避的，我不是好和多和区
No, no, no, am. 1am.
不，我是说真的
Is that your parents?
他们是你的区爸妈妈 ?
That's it, Dad! Plan B!
那就是B计划
All we have to do is weave through traffic through town square
我们只要穿遇疯狂的车了午
while avoiding death rays from alien robots.
避并外星机器人的死光
We get to Town Hall, climb up to the roof
爬到市政廉屋顶最高的地方
and give the kid back to its parents.
把小朋友膛给他和区妈就行
Yeah!
好啊
Charge!
街啊 !
Now that's what I call takin’ out the trash!
这才算清理垃圾六
OK, son. Now what?
好了，现在怎广办 ?
Fire truck!
消防车 !
Plan C!
C计划
Runt, no! Turn around!
乳猪，快掉头
- Go back to Town Hall! - But they'll vaporize us!
回到市政廉 我们会被打死耶
- You want me to do what? - Runt, just do it! It'll work!
你要我做什么 ? 快点，一定行的
We'll survive!
我们会活下去
I will survive?
我会活下去?
Brake, Abby!
踩黎车!
OK.
好
Floor it!
踊油门 !
Deploy ladder, Fish!
和急干，拨动云梯
I'll survive
我会活下去
Plan D.
D计划
But loving you! Full support!
(十楼)
I can't get out! Come back, son!
我出不去 回来，儿子
We can't go out this way! It's dangerous.
这和里出不去，太危险了
- No, Dad, I can do this! - It's too dangerous.
不会，我可以的 太危险了
I can do this. I can.
我真的可以
You gotta believe me this time.
这坎你一定要相信我
I do, son.
我相信你，儿子
OK, hang on tight.
好吧，抓紧了
- Yes! - Here's your kid! Look over here!
好耶 你们的小孩在这壬
Here's your kid!
你们小孩在这和里
He's OK!
他没事
He's all right! Stop the invasion!
他温事，停止攻击
Son! Son!
儿子 ! 儿子 !
- I'm here, son! - Dad! Look out!
我来了 和爸，小心
Get away from my boy! Get away!
准我儿子速一点
The mighty Acorns...
伟大的橡果巍
Tic Tac?
口香代 ?
Why did you take our child?
你贺什么拐走我们的小孩 ?
Just... Just hold on there, buddy!
等一下，老兄
My son did not take your kid!
我儿子没有拐走他
You were the one that left him behind!
是你们总了把他带走
That's bad parenting! And I should know!
这征父母很不负责任 我最清楚了
Silence!
于现 !
Release the child!
把小孩放并 !
- OK. - OK, OK.
好 好吧
Sweetheart! Oh, Kirby, I'm so happy to see you! My darling!
北鼻，我见到你好高要哦 我的心肝裤上中
- That was close. - At least they're back together.
好险哦 至少他们一家团圆了
They got their kid.
他们找回小孩了
You have violated intergalactic law 90210!
你们违反了银河系法90210
A charge punishable by immediate particle disintegration!
最严属的咪习是粒子分解
Oh, snap.
这下惨了
What's that?
你说什么 ?
I don't quite...
我孤不懂…
Melvin, honey? He's saying they're telling the truth.
巴文，老公 他说他们说的是实话
It was just a misunderstanding.
这只是一场误会
Well, then. This is awkward.
那我就粮大了
- Yes, it is. - [suppose I should...
是啊 我猜我应该…
- Put the big guns away? - Yes, yes.
把大检拿开 好，好
- Now put them down. - Of course.
把他们放下来 没问题
- And turn off your big voice. - But I don't...
天掉大声公 可是我…
- Turn it off. - But...
快天掉 可是…
But I don't get to use the big voice very often!
我都没机会用到大志公
Melvin.
巴文
Yes, dear.
好啦，老逆
Hi. Anyone want to try the big voice?
，有人想试用大声公吗 ?
Again, I cannot tell you how sorry we are for this whole misunderstanding.
我们钨这场误会感到很抱娄
We are. And if it hadn't been for your son there,
要不是有你儿子
well, we might have vaporized the whole planet.
我们就会毁减整个地球
What?
什么 ?
Goodness! What a shame that would have been.
天啊，那就太可惜了
- Tell ‘em! - Where would we pick acorns?
陵他们说 我们就摘不到橡树果了
We stop here on the way to the in-laws.
她回娘家都会路通过儿
- Every year. - Looked on all the other planets.
每年一定来 我们找遇其它星球
- You only find them on Earth. - It says here.
地球才有全宇最访的橡桂果 这是广告看板上面说的
That caught our eyes.
那引起我们的注意
OK, everything's been put back to normal,
搞定了，一切都恢复原状
except for this one, over here.
除了这一个
Hi, y‘all!
大家好
Foxy?
狐狸业 ?
Lollipop...
棒棒糖
She got her brainwaves scrambled during reconstitution.
恢复原状时她的胶波被弄妃
No worries! We can put her back the way she was.
放心，我可以把她变回来
No! She's perfect.
不，她这样很好
Lollipop!
棒棒糖 !
Darling! Look at the time! We better get a move on.
老娑，看看我的键 我们得走了
All right, then. It was good meetin’ ya.
好吧，很高旨认识你
Sorry for the whole full-scale invasion thing.
我为入侵行动向你道刍
But, hey, I'm a dad. You know how it is with your kids.
不明我是个和区 做什计全是为了小孩
When they need ya, you do whatever it takes.
当他们需要你 你什么都顾意做
There goes that panel again.
这乾板子又掉下来了
Every year we come, this thing falls off.
每年来地球都会掉下来
Seriously, honey, someday it's going to hit somebody on the head.
名有一天会K到别人的头
- Nonsense! - You can't return the panel, can you?
胡说八道 你不能拿去退货吗 ?
- Now that's ridiculous. - You threw away the receipt again.
不行啦 你又把发村再丢了
Silence!
于现 !
Melvin, did you just try and use the big voice on me?
你竞敢大融跟我说话 ?
Who we talkin’ about?
我们在说谁呀?
So I'd like to see the movie they make about you now.
我倒想看他们怎广拍这部电影
I just hope they stay true to what really happened.
我只希望能患尖真实故事
Oh, son, these people are from Hollywood!
儿子，这些人来自好菜坊 !
One thing they'll never do...
(一年后)
..1S mess with a good story.
(四眼天蕉 真实故事改编)
Red alert! Man your battle stations! Status report, Mr. Fish.
准备作战，各就各位 和急干，报告状况
Commander Little, the evil Foxloxian Army
难丁指挥官 那恶的狐狸精部内
has broken through the planet's atmosphere.
…已经衡进地球大气导
But that means...
那代表…-
Yes, I know. The sky... is falling.
我知道，天空掉下来了
Commander Little! No!
难丁指挥官，不!
Please... call me...
请你叫我
Oh, Ace! No!
英雄，不!
I never intended to bring you into this... Abby.
我不是故意把拉进来 鸭比
- Runt, do you copy? - Yes, commander?
乳猪，收到吗? 收到，指挥官
Runt, my friend, an alien fleet is about to invade Earth.
乳猪，好兄弟 外星人就快入优地球
Civilization as we know it depends on me
整个文明都要靠我择救
and, to a lesser extent... you.
有一小部份也要靠你
So I've just got one question for you:
我只想问你一个问题
Are you ready to rock?
你准备迎战了吗 ?
Ain't no mountain high enough, ain't no valley low...
上刀山下油编，在死不异
Raise your pork shield, Runt. Prepare to engage.
刻动猪油保护畦，淮人备迎灿
Stay on target. Stay on target!
虹准目标
Give 'em a taste of the other white meat!
让他们党党 你乱影猪脚的属害 !
Cap'n! Look out!
秀长 ”小心
Runt!
乳和猪 !
Runt, are you all right?
乳猪，你没事吧 ?
No, no. Ya gotta go on without me, commander.
我没救了，别管我
Just leave me some ammo, a little water,
给我一点弹药，一点水
some chips if you have ‘em.
有的话顺便给我一些暮片
This is amazingly accurate.
这完全符合事实
He was my good friend.
他是我的超级好朋友
Oh, Abby.
嗅，鸣比
At least I still have you... Abby.
至少我还有和，鸣比
- Ace! - Abby.
英雄 ! 鸭比!
Good people of Oakey Oaks.
各位橡果镇镇民
Though at times it may feel like the sky is falling around you,
路然你们有了时候会党得 天快要需下来
. never give up.
但是不要放素
For every day... is a new day!
每天都是菜新的一天
A new day!
霖新的一天
Oh, Ace!
噢，英雄
Don't go breaking my heart
不要伤我的心
! couldn't if I tried
我就算想也办不到
Oh, honey, if! get restless
如果我抓狂发躯
Baby, you're not that kind
你不是那种疯子
And nobody knows it
没有人知道
- When I! was down - l was your clown
当我心情浊丽 我会当你的小王
And nobody knows it
没有人知道
Right from the start
我第一眼见到你
I gave you my heart
就把心交给你
Don't go breaking my heart
不要伤我的心
! won't go breaking your heart
我不会伤你的心
Don't go breaking my
不要伤我的…不要伤我的…
Don't go breaking my heart
不要伤我的心
! won't go breaking your heart
我不会伤你的心
Don't go breaking my
不要伤我的…不要伤我的…
Don't go breaking my heart
不要伤我的心
Come on, Runt. You can do it.
加油，扎猪，你可以的
Don't go breaking my ! won't go breaking your heart
我不会伤你的心
You got to act quickly, Dad. Try this.
你要快吕 ? 试斌这一招
- Don't go breaking my - There you go!
不要伤我的… 这就对了
- There it is!
很好
! won't go breaking your heart
我不会伤你的心
I'm having fun now!
我玩得好开心哦
Don't go breaking my heart
不要伤我的心
That was great!
粹采了
Let's sing it again!
再唱一遍